[opening theme music playing]
ALGAMA BOTANICAL GARDEN
EMPLOYEES ONLY
BACK ENTRANCE
UDON BEBEBE
[Legoshi] I'm from Udon Bebebe.
I'm here to pick up the bowls.
[Legoshi grunts]
[rustling]
[female staff screams]
- [female staff grunts in pain]
- [Legoshi] Huh? Ah, are you all right?
[female staff]
Am I all right? Did you see that fall?
I let a butterfly escape.
[Legoshi] A butterfly?
I've been waiting for it to come out.
[Legoshi] Uh... [inhales]
So, um, would you like me
to help you find it?
- Huh?
- Well, tell me what it looks like.
It's blue.
And it's got wings about this wide.
Ah. A Ulysses butterfly.
Uh... No, it's a morpho butterfly.
Oh, one of those. Hmm.
Um...
Hmm.
- Oh. Can I borrow this jar?
- [female staff] I guess.
Do you have any aluminum foil?
Uh, yeah.
Stay here, just give me a second. [grunts]
[door closes]
[Legoshi] Morpho butterflies
are attracted to blue reflections.
Oh, good to know!
[Legoshi] Yeah, they think
it's one of their own.
You know, they also really like
sugarcane juice and over-ripened fruit.
[ethereal shimmering]
Hey!
[gasps] Look at that!
[Legoshi] Oh, wow.
It's so beautiful.
[female staff] It really is, isn't it?
[Legoshi] All right, get your net.
You ready?
[female staff] Oh. Oh, yeah, right.
- [exhales]
- [ethereal shimmering]
[grunts with effort] Ah!
Nice catch!
Ah. [laughs exultantly]
You really saved me.
You are a butterfly whisperer.
[laughs sheepishly]
I wish! Just a hobby of mine. [inhales]
Ever think about coming to work here?
I can get you an application. Huh?
Oh, no. I'm good.
Someone has to deliver the noodles.
You can think about it, right?
Yeah. I will.
Hmm.
Well, it would be
a pretty nice place to work.
SIX TAILS IN A ROW
And I'm back!
[Sunaga grunts with exertion]
You took long enough.
Let's get moving.
You wanna make up for your sick leave,
I need you to work a little harder.
Those dishes are ready.
Tempura for table two.
- [Legoshi] Yeah. Got it.
- [Sunaga] Wait! Not that one.
Look at the order notes.
[Legoshi] Oh, sorry.
[Sunaga] Table two is canine.
We can't serve them onions.
[Legoshi] Oh, yeah, I see.
Be careful.
We're not gonna stay in business
if we're getting carnivores sick.
Right. You're right.
- [horn honking]
- [vehicle passing]
[Sunaga] Oh. Almost forgot.
You got a call from a friend.
Really? Which one?
[indistinct chatter]
[Fudge] Guys! Hearing anything good?
[sighs in exasperation]
Go shut that guy up.
Um...
FESTIVAL OF THE METEOR SCRIPT
[Gon] Your script for the new stage play.
I read it.
Personally, I think plays
about friendships
between carnivores and herbivores
aren't nearly
as palatable as they once were.
[both sigh]
[Gon] But this one's different.
You are trying to overcome
those old tropes and cliches, right?
Right.
[Gon] Hmm.
Don't you worry.
I'll handle things with the committee.
[Els] So that means...
So that means you can stage your play.
- [Bill laughing] Yes!
- [Els laughing]
Hang on, calm down now.
- We still have rules here.
- [Els] Uh...
Oh, right. Sorry, sir.
This has real potential.
A touching friendship
between fangs and horns.
"Our love is an oasis in the arid desert."
Nice line!
[chuckling] Yes!
We did it!
[Ellen] It's taking too long.
[sighs] It's my fault
if it doesn't work out.
Didn't you say you were confident?
- [Ellen] Oh!
- [all grunting]
[Kibi] Wait for me!
- [Fudge] Oh, boy.
- [others gasp]
[indistinct chatter]
[Gon] Hmm...
Festival of the Meteor.
Certainly exciting.
- [all speaking indistinctly]
- [door closes]
[all cheering]
- We did it, Tao buddy!
- Oh, man, it's all thanks to you!
- Oh, I'd give you a hug if I could!
- Well, let's get this wall out of here!
It's in the way of us building set pieces.
- [Bill] Not so fast.
- [Fudge] Huh?
- [Bill] Doesn't work that way.
- [Kai] Why not?
During the prep period, we are supposed
to remain as two separate clubs.
We can't avoid it during performance,
but until then we stay separated.
- [Fudge] Seriously?
- [Els] We still have our rules.
Let's be grateful we got approval.
Thanks to Kibi and Tao
for writing such a great script.
[gentle applause]
Well...
- You rock!
- Come on now, that's enough.
Thank you, guys.
You know, from here on out,
we are all gonna to have to step it up.
I think Juno should play the lead role.
The carnivore protagonist.
- What do you say?
- [Juno] What?
[inhales] Okay!
[Ellen] So let's figure out
who will play the herbivore hero.
For a story about friendship
between horns and fangs,
it would be best
to pick someone with horns.
Pina can do it.
Pina's horns would really stand out.
Even though
his last performance got canceled,
I think we can all agree,
he was really good in rehearsals.
So that's why, I would nominate him.
[exhales] I agree.
But he quit the club, right?
He quit
because we were forced to stay separate.
But now we have approval
to work together. Right? Right?
I don't know.
I'm not sure I can convince him.
We can try.
Let's see, how about this?
- Hey, Juno!
- Me?
[Bill] You are in the same year as Pina.
Maybe he can be convinced by his costar.
Also, he'll listen to a girl.
He'll at least consider your invitation.
[Juno] Uh, yeah, but...
[Bill] Listen up.
The first step on the long journey
towards getting this show off the ground
is get Pina back on board.
Uh... Uh...
Juno, the success
of the Festival of the Meteor
now rests on your shoulders!
- Me? Well, uh...
- [Els] Juno, we can count on you, right?
Uh... Yes.
Why would it have to be Pina
of all people?
He quit the club!
He skipped rehearsals,
he was disrespectful to classmates,
his ridiculously well-groomed fur,
give me a break!
Coming to the herbivore floor?
The old rooftop should be empty.
Okay, there then!
[Juno sighing in irritation]
I kind of hope he doesn't show up.
GARDENING CLUB
[Juno] Oh, that's right.
This club was shut down.
[Haru] I really appreciate the help.
I didn't think you would actually say yes.
[Juno] We went through all that effort
to plant these together...
Coming to water them
is the least I could have done.
[Pina] So what's all this?
Is gardening going to be
one of your new hobbies or something?
That's a little surprising.
I wouldn't necessarily say
I'm into gardening,
but I appreciate the effort
that goes into it.
[Pina] I suppose a club is nothing
without its members, eh?
[scoffs]
Suddenly hearing from you out of the blue
was a surprise.
Let me guess. You're wanting me
to come back to the drama club.
Well-- I mean...
Well, you are short
on herbivore actors, right?
[chuckles]
Or maybe you just wanted to ask me out.
What?
[laughs dismissively]
No, don't be silly.
You are right about the club.
For the festival,
we have permission to let carnivores
and herbivores perform together.
Here's the thing.
There's a really great role for you
in this script.
The role's a double lead,
and I would be your costar.
Come on, Juno. This is on you.
You've got to convince him!
FESTIVAL OF THE METEOR SCRIPT
This play needs Pina to pull off the lead.
And now everyone thinks
this is all up to me,
that I can pull this thing off.
But I get it,
you are probably too busy, right?
- Huh?
- You know, it's okay.
It's not like it's
an end-of-the-world thing or something.
I bet you've got a lot going on.
I'll just let everyone know
you are into gardening now.
Come on. I have plenty of free time.
- Oh.
- [chuckling] I get it.
My guess is the club seniors asked you
to come here and convince me.
But I bet you yourself don't want me back.
[chuckles] Because if I'm there,
the spotlight on you
won't shine as bright.
- Unbelievable.
- [mischievous music playing]
Something I've noticed about you.
You are the type
who isn't afraid to play dirty.
You'll do anything
to get exactly what you want.
Huh, you've got some nerve!
It doesn't matter to me
if you come back or not.
- I don't need you to do me...
- Oh.
...some kind of favor!
I've got more than enough skills and looks
to outshine you any day.
Wow.
So you are dropping
your harmless carnivore act for me.
I insist you drop yours first.
You play it safe because you are afraid
if you give it your all and you fail,
then what?
If I give it my all,
it's you that's gonna be afraid.
[scoffs] You wish.
In rehearsals, you could be fantastic,
but if you can't deliver on stage,
so what?
Like you've ever seen me on stage.
I bet you were relieved
when the last show got canceled.
Were you the one behind that?
[chuckles softly] Awful lot of effort
just to avoid being near me.
Thank you, but I'll have to decline.
Well, that's fine by me,
because I decline!
[stage light switches on]
We need to stop
this insufferable fighting!
Our inexhaustible well of love
is our oasis in this arid desert!
- We were so right to get Pina for this!
- Yeah.
[Juno] Unbelievable!
I wish he really had declined!
[Melon]
When you are on a university campus,
you get to witness
such interesting things.
[male hyena] Hey, what's up?
Here are your notes from last week.
You are awesome.
- Does it all make sense?
- Sure.
You wouldn't happen to have microeconomics
for me?
- [female deer] Well...
- [Melon] They are no longer children,
and not quite adults.
But when carnivores interact
with herbivores,
their true nature reveals itself.
The carnivore's gaze finds its way
to the most appetizing parts.
While the herbivore remains
wholly unaware.
[female deer] Here.
Oh, uh, yeah. Thanks a lot.
- [Melon] This eternal dynamic...
- Later then.
[Melon] ...it makes me jealous.
Eating meat after struggling so long
to suppress your instincts...
It must taste twice as sweet.
[knock on door]
Yes?
It's Haru, the freshman studying botany.
[Melon] Mmm.
Come in.
Hope I'm not a bother.
[Melon] Ah, hello again.
Have a seat.
Thank you very much.
[Melon] Trouble sleeping?
Been eating all right?
Uh...
[Melon] It must have been quite a shock.
A young one like you
witnessing something like that.
Oh...
Yeah, but I'm fine.
It's just that I don't know
what I should do.
[Melon] You mentioned
you saw someone, right?
Yeah.
It could be my imagination,
it was so fast.
- [Melon] Did you tell the police?
- No, I didn't.
Still though...
I do wonder, if...
[Melon] Huh.
So if I'm not mistaken,
you have a theory that someone
might have pushed the professor?
Maybe.
[Melon] What about suicide? An accident?
Well, I found this feather, by the body.
- [Melon] Hmm. A pigeon, perhaps?
- [mysterious music playing]
Someone was there.
[Melon] So this pigeon was involved?
[sighs] I know it's not concrete evidence.
[exhales]
[Melon] So if we assume this was a crime...
Um...
[Melon] ...then that means whoever did this
is still out there on the loose.
They might be out there plotting
and scheming
to take down the next target.
If they think you saw what they did,
their sights could be set on you.
Oh... Hmm...
[mysterious music continues]
Oh, I get it now. I'm just being dramatic.
[Melon] Huh?
T-Thank you, I get what you're saying.
My imagination is getting the better of me
and I'm overthinking it.
- [Melon] Uh...
- I've almost been killed
a few times before, so...
[chuckling] ...of course my brain
is jumping straight to murder.
It must be a dwarf rabbit thing.
Know what I mean?
- [Melon] Uh, yeah. [laughs]
- [laughs]
If the police are saying
it was an accident,
who am I to question them?
[Melon] Hmm.
Do you think it could have been suicide?
I guess I wouldn't know.
However, if it was suicide,
she must have known she had other options.
[Melon] Huh, don't people commit suicide
when they think they're out of options?
If you commit suicide, it must mean
you know you'll be alive tomorrow.
- [Melon] Hmm.
- That's why I don't understand it.
I've lived every day thinking
it might be the last day that I'm alive.
[Melon] If that's true,
why bother with trying to get a degree?
If you think you're going to die anyway.
[chuckling] Come on. It's not as bleak
as you are making it sound.
It's like, even if I think I might die,
there are still some things
I hope I might achieve.
I still have goals and dreams.
[Melon] This little one intrigues me.
Even through her foreboding
and her mortal dread,
she's not willing throw away her chance
at a good life.
I guess I should talk to the police
just in case.
I'm so glad you invited me here.
Thank you very much.
[Melon] Yeah, very well then.
[chuckles softly].
Oh? [sniffs]
It smells like rain.
Looks like rain will be here soon.
[Melon]
Haru, the Botany Department freshman.
If you're going to the police,
I should take you.
[Haru] What?
[Melon] You shouldn't do
something like this by yourself.
Don't worry, I can drive us.
And like you said, the rain's on its way.
[ominous music playing]
[thunderclap]
[Boss panting]
[Kolo] Come on, Boss, hop on.
[Boss grunting in exertion] Thanks!
Wonder if he's already here.
Just keep your cool.
I'm excited to see our friend too,
but let's not make fools of ourselves.
Yeah, you are right.
But being so mature all day long
is not the easiest thing in the world.
It's getting kind of exhausting.
I hear ya on that one.
Still, let's try to keep it cool today.
We are not freshmen.
Yeah, that's true.
[Jack excitedly] Oh, there he is!
Hey! Look who's here!
[softly] Stay cool, guys.
- [Kolo and Durham] Cool.
- [Boss] Yeah, got it.
All right.
[gentle music playing]
[all panting]
[panting, laughs]
- [Legoshi laughing]
- [all speaking excitedly]
I tried to keep my cool,
but come on, can you guys blame me?
- What's it like living by yourself?
- [chuckles] Well, there's ups and downs.
I've been sleeping in your bed, Legoshi!
So, what do you say?
Time to get wild, right?
[all howling]
- [Miguno] That's it!
- [Durham] Yeah!
Time to let loose!
- Off the hizzy!
- Let's go wild!
All the wild, none of the shame.
[Kolo] You are talking my language.
I don't know
about giving in to my instincts, though...
- [Jack] Don't worry, it's a safe space.
- Right...
[Leisure facility announcer] I want
to welcome our B-Strike visitors today.
Go have some fun!
[kangaroos snoring]
KANGAROO CORNER
[Legoshi] Letting your wild instincts
creep into your daily life is pretty...
taboo.
[all yelling]
FELINE CORNER
[Legoshi] That's why it's important
that every species
has a place to let all their urges out.
SQUIRREL CORNER
[Legoshi]
Which is why B-Strike is so popular.
[all panting]
CANINE CORNER
[Jack] This is it.
[lights chime]
[light countdown pinging]
Oh, the anticipation is real.
- My tail's going to wag right off.
- I will not lose!
Me neither!
[Miguno]
Hey, Legoshi, tired of living alone yet?
[Legoshi]
Sometimes it gets a bit too quiet.
But it makes times like this fun!
Yeah, pretty soon we're gonna be too busy
with all our exams.
Oh, I forgot, entrance exams.
- [Legoshi] Oh!
- [Boss whoops]
[male canine laughs]
- [all panting and shouting excitedly]
- [upbeat music playing]
- [indistinct shouting]
- [Kolo] Woah!
[both grunt]
[grunts in pain]
Oh, that's mine!
[straining] I got it!
- Come on, toss it back!
- Is it okay if I do it?
- Do it!
- Let's go!
- Yeah, it's your ball!
- Let loose!
[panting]
[Legoshi] Bringing a ball
back to where it came from...
Only canines understand. What a rush!
CONGRATULATIONS
[female voice on machine] Amazing!
Your return is today's fastest record!
Congratulations on being number one!
You are so special!
[all cheering]
I'm a good boy!
Yes! Yeah!
[Legoshi]
Now, this is the life of a canine!
[upbeat music fades out]
[Boss] Ah...
[Jack] We're definitely gonna be
sore tomorrow. [chuckles]
[Miguno] Is it weird that I don't care?
So, guys...
have you all picked a career?
Seems like
we have to make our minds up soon.
We can't all be outlaws like you.
[chuckling]
You know, I'm thinking about it too.
Durham, you sticking with swimming?
Mmm, guess so. I got recommended.
Boss is taking over the family business.
[Boss] Yeah, that's right.
[Legoshi] Eventually, I guess,
we all have to find our own paths.
It's not like we didn't know
it would happen.
I just thought that, somehow,
we'd always be together
back in room 701.
[grunting with effort]
Hey, guys,
do you think after we're all adults,
we'll still hang out like this sometimes?
Uh...
What are you talking about?
- Of course we will.
- [male canine chuckling] Yeah.
- All of us are canines for life, right?
- [all chuckling]
All you need to do is howl
and we'll all be there!
- [Miguno] That goes without saying!
- [indistinct]
[all laughing]
Looking forward
to seeing your place, Lego-face.
You do keep it clean, don't you?
[Legoshi] Hmm?
There's not much there to tidy up.
I'd invite everyone,
but the walls are so thin.
[inhales] We'd make too much noise
for the neighbors.
Yeah, we are loud.
Well, I mean, I know how to behave myself.
Y'know, I got those good boy manners.
[chuckles]
Eh... You had my grandpa yelling at you
last time you were over.
[laughing] Come on,
I was only nine years old!
All right, meet you there.
[Legoshi] Hmm?
Oh... Hmm...
Hmm.
HAZARDOUS MATERIALS LIST
CANINES: ONIONS
[Legoshi] It's strange.
We've always been together.
And I never thought
there'd be an end in sight.
Who would have guessed
that Jack had a secret?
[closing theme song playing]